<Level id='0'>A young monk approached his teacher and said, =Master, I have spent years studying the manuscripts, meditating and following your wisdom, and yet I am no closer to attaining the truth than I was when I began studying.

Tell me, when will I reach enlightenment?=

The master said, =You seek silence and yet refuse to listen. You seek beauty and yet keep your eyes shut. Your studies have not even begun.=

The monk was not satisfied with the answer.

With a weary heart, he headed for the east at dawn, leaving what little he had back at the temple.</Level>

<Level id='1'>The first few days were filled with wonder. The young monk discovered the world he has been sheltered from for so many years.</Level>

<Level id='2'>His body, so inadequately prepared for strain and effort, was now moving and running and pushing.</Level>

<Level id='3'>He climbed trees with surprising dexterity, drunk with the feeling of being alive.</Level>

<Level id='4'>The monk had no shortage of time. A little patience, and his surroundings were quick to change.</Level>

<Level id='5'>But... slowly but surely, this newfound freedom stopped being the source of amusement.</Level>

<Level id='6'>=There must be another mode of existence, beyond this mortal shell!= the monk cried out.</Level>

<Level id='7'>The new form gave the young monk a surprising perspective on life.</Level>

<Level id='8'>As a boar, the monk was quick to give in to his more violent urges.</Level>

<Level id='9'>But soon, even this existence ran out of amusements to offer. He next wished to soar into the sky.</Level>

<Level id='10'>Having already lived a dozen lives, the monk started questioning his real self.</Level>

<Level id='11'>Was he a monk who became a bird or a bird who became a monk? This circular question had no beginning, and no end.</Level>

<Level id='12'>Again, the monk grew weary of his earthly boundaries. He sought to shed his skin once more.</Level>

<Level id='13'>Against expectations, his new existence did nothing to satiate his avarice. He still felt hunger for the truth.</Level>

<Level id='14'>For all the forms the monk has attained, he did not think it possible to let go of his ego and truly become one with the world.</Level>

<Level id='15'>Overcome with depression, the monk felt as though turning into PRETA, an ever-hungry demon.</Level>

<Level id='16'>He could not tell whether this new form was feeding on his grief, or if his grief was strengthened by his new form.</Level>

<Level id='17'>It was a miserable experience, and yet... strangely, he kept going.</Level>

<Level id='18'>Over time, he began to find some strange strength in his abject powerlessness.</Level>

<Level id='19'>In his mind, he kept returning to all the past lives he has lived.</Level>

<Level id='20'>At long last, a breakthrough was made.</Level>

<Level id='21'>In the dance of Samsara,
puzzles mirror life's challenges, 
and our transformations echo the impermanence of identity. 


As monks, we grapple with the bittersweet truth 
that suffering is woven into the fabric of existence.


Yet, in the quiet contemplation, 
we find the resilience to navigate life's intricate maze, 
knowing that within the shadows, 
the light of enlightenment awaits.


THANK YOU for playing!</Level>

<Level id='1.1'>pc</Level>
<Level id='1.11'>mobile</Level>

<Level id='2.1'>Push to move wooden crates</Level>
<Level id='2.11'>Push to move wooden crates</Level>

<Level id='3.1'>W or Up Arrow to climb a tree</Level>
<Level id='3.11'>Press Up Button to climb a tree</Level>

<Level id='4.1'>S or Down Arrow Key to let time pass</Level>
<Level id='4.11'>Tap Down to let time pass</Level>

<Level id='5.1'>R to reset</Level>
<Level id='5.11'>Tap to reset</Level>

<Level id='6.1'>RIGHT and LEFT to spin the Samsara wheel, Up and Down to resurrect as a new life form</Level>
<Level id='6.11'>Tap RIGHT and LEFT to spin the Samsara wheel, Up and Down to resurrect as a new life form</Level>

<Level id='7.1'>Only a human can ring the bell</Level>
<Level id='7.11'>Only a human can ring the bell</Level>

<Level id='8.1'>BOAR can destroy some blocks</Level>
<Level id='8.11'>BOAR can destroy some blocks</Level>

<Level id='9.1'>BIRD can push light crates and float by holding W or UP</Level>
<Level id='9.11'>BIRD can push light crates and float by holding UP</Level>

<Level id='10.1'>BIRD can use nests as platforms</Level>
<Level id='10.11'>BIRD can use nests as platforms</Level>

<Level id='11.1'>Press Down to lay an egg as bird</Level>
<Level id='11.11'>Press Down to lay an egg as bird</Level>

<Level id='12.1'>SNAKE moves in four directions and can push light crates</Level>
<Level id='12.11'>SNAKE moves in four directions and can push light crates</Level>

<Level id='13.1'>SNAKE can eat BIRD's egg to grow longer</Level>
<Level id='13.11'>SNAKE can eat BIRD's egg to grow longer</Level>

<Level id='14.1'></Level>
<Level id='14.11'></Level>

<Level id='15.1'>Press S or Down to teleport between tombstones. PRETA is cleansed with bell chime</Level>
<Level id='15.11'>Press Down to teleport between tombstones. PRETA is cleansed with bell chime</Level>

<Level id='16.1'>PRETA cannot die</Level>
<Level id='16.11'>PRETA cannot die</Level>

<Level id='17.1'>You can only teleport tombstones of the same type</Level>
<Level id='17.11'>You can only teleport tombstones of the same type</Level>




italian-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
<Level id='99'>Un giovane monaco si avvicino al suo maestro e disse, "Maestro, ho trascorso anni studiando i manoscritti, meditando e seguendo la tua saggezza, eppure non sono piu vicino a raggiungere la verita di quanto lo ero quando ho iniziato a studiare.

Dimmi, quando raggiungero l'illuminazione?"

Il maestro disse, "Cerchi il silenzio eppure ti rifiuti di ascoltare. Cerchi la bellezza eppure tieni gli occhi chiusi. I tuoi studi non sono neanche iniziati."

Il monaco non fu soddisfatto della risposta.

Con un cuore stanco, si diresse verso est all'alba, lasciando cio che aveva poco nel tempio.</Level>

<Level id='100'>I primi giorni furono pieni di meraviglia. Il giovane monaco scopri il mondo da cui era stato riparato per cosi tanti anni.</Level>

<Level id='200'>Il suo corpo, cosi inadeguatamente preparato per sforzi e fatiche, ora si muoveva, correva e spingeva.</Level>

<Level id='300'>Scalava alberi con una destrezza sorprendente, ubriaco dalla sensazione di essere vivo.</Level>

<Level id='400'>Al monaco non mancava il tempo. Un po' di pazienza, e i suoi dintorni cambiavano rapidamente.</Level>

<Level id='500'>Ma... lentamente ma sicuramente, questa nuova liberta smise di essere fonte di divertimento.</Level>

<Level id='600'>"Deve esserci un altro modo di esistere, oltre questa corazza mortale!" grido il monaco.</Level>

<Level id='700'>La nuova forma diede al giovane monaco una prospettiva sorprendente sulla vita.</Level>

<Level id='800'>Come un cinghiale, il monaco cedeva rapidamente ai suoi impulsi piu violenti.</Level>

<Level id='900'>Ma presto, anche questa esistenza finì per non offrire piu divertimenti. Desidero quindi sollevarsi in cielo.</Level>

<Level id='1000'>Avendo gia vissuto una dozzina di vite, il monaco inizio a interrogarsi sul suo vero se.</Level>

<Level id='1100'>Era lui un monaco diventato uccello o un uccello diventato monaco? Questa domanda circolare non aveva inizio ne fine.</Level>

<Level id='1200'>Ancora una volta, il monaco si stanco dei suoi limiti terreni. Cerco di liberarsi dalla sua pelle ancora una volta.</Level>

<Level id='1300'>Contro ogni aspettativa, la sua nuova esistenza non fece nulla per saziare la sua bramosia. Sentiva ancora fame di verita.</Level>

<Level id='1400'>Per tutte le forme che il monaco aveva assunto, non pensava fosse possibile lasciare andare il suo ego e diventare veramente uno con il mondo.</Level>

<Level id='1500'>Sopraffatto dalla depressione, il monaco si senti come se si trasformasse in PRETA, un demone sempre affamato.</Level>

<Level id='1600'>Non poteva dire se questa nuova forma si stesse nutrendo della sua tristezza, o se la sua tristezza fosse rafforzata dalla sua nuova forma.</Level>

<Level id='1700'>Fu un'esperienza miserabile eppure... stranamente, continuava.</Level>

<Level id='1800'>Con il tempo, comincio a trovare una strana forza nella sua totale impotenza.</Level>

<Level id='1900'>Nella sua mente, tornava sempre a tutte le vite passate che aveva vissuto.</Level>

<Level id='2000'>Finalmente, fu fatto un grande passo avanti.</Level>

<Level id='2100'>Nella danza di Samsara,
i puzzle riflettono le sfide della vita,
e le nostre trasformazioni echeggiano l'impermanenza dell'identita.

Come monaci, lottiamo con la verita agrodolce
che la sofferenza e intessuta nella trama dell'esistenza.

Eppure, nella quieta contemplazione,
troviamo la resilienza per navigare nel labirinto intricato della vita,
sapendo che nelle ombre,
la luce dell'illuminazione ci attende.

GRAZIE per aver giocato!</Level>



<Level id='1.1'>pc</Level>
<Level id='1.11'>mobile</Level>

<Level id='2.12'>Spingi per spostare le casse di legno</Level>
<Level id='2.112'>Spingi per spostare le casse di legno</Level>

<Level id='3.12'>W o Freccia Su per arrampicarti su un albero</Level>
<Level id='3.112'>Premi il pulsante Su per arrampicarti su un albero</Level>

<Level id='4.12'>S o Tasto Freccia Giu per far passare il tempo</Level>
<Level id='4.112'>Tocca Giu per far passare il tempo</Level>

<Level id='5.12'>R per ripristinare</Level>
<Level id='5.112'>Tocca per ripristinare</Level>

<Level id='6.12'>DESTRA e SINISTRA per far girare la ruota di Samsara, Su e Giu per resuscitare come una nuova forma di vita</Level>
<Level id='6.112'>Tocca DESTRA e SINISTRA per far girare la ruota di Samsara, Su e Giu per resuscitare come una nuova forma di vita</Level>

<Level id='7.12'>Solo un umano puo suonare la campana</Level>
<Level id='7.112'>Solo un umano puo suonare la campana</Level>

<Level id='8.12'>IL CINGHIALE puo distruggere alcuni blocchi</Level>
<Level id='8.112'>IL CINGHIALE puo distruggere alcuni blocchi</Level>

<Level id='9.12'>L'UCCCELLO puo spingere casse leggere e fluttuare tenendo premuto W o SU</Level>
<Level id='9.112'>L'UCCCELLO puo spingere casse leggere e fluttuare tenendo premuto SU</Level>

<Level id='10.12'>L'UCCCELLO puo usare i nidi come piattaforme</Level>
<Level id='10.112'>L'UCCCELLO puo usare i nidi come piattaforme</Level>

<Level id='11.12'>Premi Giu per deporre un uovo come uccello</Level>
<Level id='11.112'>Premi Giu per deporre un uovo come uccello</Level>

<Level id='12.12'>Il SERPENTE si muove in quattro direzioni e puo spingere casse leggere</Level>
<Level id='12.112'>Il SERPENTE si muove in quattro direzioni e puo spingere casse leggere</Level>

<Level id='13.12'>Il SERPENTE puo mangiare l'uovo dell'UCCCELLO per crescere piu lungo</Level>
<Level id='13.112'>Il SERPENTE puo mangiare l'uovo dell'UCCCELLO per crescere piu lungo</Level>

<Level id='14.12'></Level>
<Level id='14.112'></Level>

<Level id='15.12'>Premi S o Giu per teletrasportarti tra le lapidi. PRETA viene purificato con il suono della campana</Level>
<Level id='15.112'>Premi Giu per teletrasportarti tra le lapidi. PRETA viene purificato con il suono della campana</Level>

<Level id='16.12'>PRETA non puo morire</Level>
<Level id='16.112'>PRETA non puo morire</Level>

<Level id='17.12'>Puoi teletrasportare solo lapidi dello stesso tipo</Level>
<Level id='17.112'>Puoi teletrasportare solo lapidi dello stesso tipo</Level>



spanish-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
<Level id='999'>Un joven monje se acerco a su maestro y dijo: =Maestro, he pasado anos estudiando los manuscritos, meditando y siguiendo tu sabiduria, y aun asi no estoy mas cerca de alcanzar la verdad que cuando comence a estudiar.

Dime, cuando alcanzare la iluminacion?=

El maestro dijo: =Buscas el silencio y sin embargo te niegas a escuchar. Buscas la belleza y sin embargo mantienes tus ojos cerrados. Tus estudios ni siquiera han comenzado.=

El monje no quedo satisfecho con la respuesta.

Con el corazon cansado, se dirigio hacia el este al amanecer, dejando atras lo poco que tenia en el templo.</Level>

<Level id='1000'>Los primeros dias estuvieron llenos de asombro. El joven monje descubrio el mundo del que habia sido protegido durante tantos anos.</Level>

<Level id='2000'>Su cuerpo, tan inadecuadamente preparado para el esfuerzo y la fatiga, ahora se movia y corria y empujaba.</Level>

<Level id='3000'>Escalaba arboles con una destreza sorprendente, embriagado por la sensacion de estar vivo.</Level>

<Level id='4000'>El monje no carecia de tiempo. Un poco de paciencia, y su entorno cambiaba rapidamente.</Level>

<Level id='5000'>Pero... lentamente, esta libertad recien encontrada dejo de ser la fuente de diversion.</Level>

<Level id='6000'>=Debe de haber otro modo de existencia, mas alla de esta cascara mortal!= grito el monje.</Level>

<Level id='7000'>La nueva forma le dio al joven monje una perspectiva sorprendente sobre la vida.</Level>

<Level id='8000'>Como jabali, el monje cedio rapidamente a sus impulsos mas violentos.</Level>

<Level id='9000'>Pero pronto, incluso esta existencia se quedo sin entretenimientos que ofrecer. Luego deseo remontarse al cielo.</Level>

<Level id='10000'>Habiendo vivido ya una docena de vidas, el monje empezo a cuestionar su verdadero ser.</Level>

<Level id='11000'>Era el un monje que se convirtio en pajaro o un pajaro que se convirtio en monje? Esta pregunta circular no tenia principio ni fin.</Level>

<Level id='12000'>Una vez mas, el monje se canso de sus limites terrenales. Busco desprenderse de su piel una vez mas.</Level>

<Level id='13000'>Contra todo pronostico, su nueva existencia no hizo nada para saciar su avaricia. Todavia sentia hambre de la verdad.</Level>

<Level id='14000'>Por todas las formas que el monje habia alcanzado, no creia posible desprenderse de su ego y realmente fundirse con el mundo.</Level>

<Level id='15000'>Abatido por la depresion, el monje sentia como si se estuviera convirtiendo en PRETA, un demonio siempre hambriento.</Level>

<Level id='16000'>No podia decir si esta nueva forma estaba alimentandose de su dolor, o si su dolor se fortalecia con su nueva forma.</Level>

<Level id='17000'>Fue una experiencia miserable, y sin embargo... extranamente, siguio adelante.</Level>

<Level id='18000'>Con el tiempo, comenzo a encontrar una extrana fuerza en su abyecta impotencia.</Level>

<Level id='19000'>En su mente, seguia volviendo a todas las vidas pasadas que habia vivido.</Level>

<Level id='20000'>Por fin, se logro un avance.</Level>

<Level id='21000'>En la danza de Samsara,
los acertijos reflejan los desafios de la vida,
y nuestras transformaciones hacen eco de la impermanencia de la identidad.

Como monjes, luchamos con la verdad agridulce
de que el sufrimiento esta tejido en el tejido de la existencia.

Sin embargo, en la contemplacion tranquila,
encontramos la fuerza para navegar por el intrincado laberinto de la vida,
sabiendo que dentro de las sombras,
la luz de la iluminacion espera.

GRACIAS por jugar!</Level>



<Level id='1.13'>pc</Level>
<Level id='1.113'>móvil</Level>

<Level id='2.13'>Presiona para mover las cajas de madera</Level>
<Level id='2.113'>Presiona para mover las cajas de madera</Level>

<Level id='3.13'>W o Flecha Arriba para trepar un arbol</Level>
<Level id='3.113'>Presiona el botón de subir para trepar un arbol</Level>

<Level id='4.13'>S o Flecha Abajo para dejar pasar el tiempo</Level>
<Level id='4.113'>Toca Abajo para dejar pasar el tiempo</Level>

<Level id='5.13'>R para reiniciar</Level>
<Level id='5.113'>Toca para reiniciar</Level>

<Level id='6.13'>DERECHA e IZQUIERDA para girar la rueda de Samsara, Arriba y Abajo para resucitar como una nueva forma de vida</Level>
<Level id='6.113'>Toca DERECHA e IZQUIERDA para girar la rueda de Samsara, Arriba y Abajo para resucitar como una nueva forma de vida</Level>

<Level id='7.13'>Solo un humano puede tocar la campana</Level>
<Level id='7.113'>Solo un humano puede tocar la campana</Level>

<Level id='8.13'>EL JABALI puede destruir algunos bloques</Level>
<Level id='8.113'>EL JABALI puede destruir algunos bloques</Level>

<Level id='9.13'>El PAJARO puede empujar cajas ligeras y flotar manteniendo presionado W o ARRIBA</Level>
<Level id='9.113'>El PAJARO puede empujar cajas ligeras y flotar manteniendo presionado ARRIBA</Level>

<Level id='10.13'>El PAJARO puede usar los nidos como plataformas</Level>
<Level id='10.113'>El PAJARO puede usar los nidos como plataformas</Level>

<Level id='11.13'>Presiona Abajo para poner un huevo como pajaro</Level>
<Level id='11.113'>Presiona Abajo para poner un huevo como pajaro</Level>

<Level id='12.13'>La SERPIENTE se mueve en cuatro direcciones y puede empujar cajas ligeras</Level>
<Level id='12.113'>La SERPIENTE se mueve en cuatro direcciones y puede empujar cajas ligeras</Level>

<Level id='13.13'>La SERPIENTE puede comerse el huevo del PAJARO para crecer mas largo</Level>
<Level id='13.113'>La SERPIENTE puede comerse el huevo del PAJARO para crecer mas largo</Level>

<Level id='14.13'></Level>
<Level id='14.113'></Level>

<Level id='15.13'>Presiona S o Abajo para teletransportarte entre las lapidas. PRETA se purifica con el tintineo de la campana</Level>
<Level id='15.113'>Presiona Abajo para teletransportarte entre las lapidas. PRETA se purifica con el tintineo de la campana</Level>

<Level id='16.13'>PRETA no puede morir</Level>
<Level id='16.113'>PRETA no puede morir</Level>

<Level id='17.13'>Solo puedes teletransportar lapidas del mismo tipo</Level>
<Level id='17.113'>Solo puedes teletransportar lapidas del mismo tipo</Level>



portugese(brasil)-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
<Level id='9999'>Um jovem monge se aproximou de seu mestre e disse: "Mestre, passei anos estudando os manuscritos, meditando e seguindo sua sabedoria, e ainda assim nao estou mais perto de alcancar a verdade do que estava quando comecei a estudar.

Diga-me, quando alcancarei a iluminacao?"

O mestre disse: "Voce busca o silencio e ainda se recusa a ouvir. Voce busca a beleza e ainda mantem os olhos fechados. Seus estudos nem mesmo comecaram."

O monge nao ficou satisfeito com a resposta.

Com um coracao cansado, ele partiu para o leste ao amanhecer, deixando para tras o pouco que tinha no templo.</Level>

<Level id='10000'>Os primeiros dias foram cheios de maravilha. O jovem monge descobriu o mundo do qual foi protegido por tantos anos.</Level>

<Level id='20000'>Seu corpo, tao inadequadamente preparado para o esforco, agora estava se movendo, correndo e empurrando.</Level>

<Level id='30000'>Ele escalava arvores com uma destreza surpreendente, embriagado pela sensacao de estar vivo.</Level>

<Level id='40000'>O monge nao tinha escassez de tempo. Um pouco de paciencia, e seu entorno mudava rapidamente.</Level>

<Level id='50000'>Mas... lentamente, essa nova liberdade deixou de ser fonte de diversao.</Level>

<Level id='60000'>"Deve haver outra forma de existencia, alem desta concha mortal!" gritou o monge.</Level>

<Level id='70000'>A nova forma deu ao jovem monge uma perspectiva surpreendente sobre a vida.</Level>

<Level id='80000'>Como um javali, o monge rapidamente cedia aos seus impulsos mais violentos.</Level>

<Level id='90000'>Mas logo, ate mesmo essa existencia ficou sem entretenimento para oferecer. Ele entao desejou voar pelo ceu.</Level>

<Level id='100000'>Tendo ja vivido uma dúzia de vidas, o monge comecou a questionar seu verdadeiro eu.</Level>

<Level id='110000'>Ele era um monge que se tornou passaro ou um passaro que se tornou monge? Essa pergunta circular nao tinha comeco nem fim.</Level>

<Level id='120000'>Novamente, o monge se cansou de suas limitacoes terrenas. Ele procurou se livrar de sua pele mais uma vez.</Level>

<Level id='130000'>Contra todas as expectativas, sua nova existencia nao fez nada para saciar sua avareza. Ele ainda sentia fome da verdade.</Level>

<Level id='140000'>Para todas as formas que o monge havia alcancado, ele nao achava possivel abandonar seu ego e realmente se tornar um com o mundo.</Level>

<Level id='150000'>Sobrecarregado pela depressao, o monge sentiu como se estivesse se transformando em PRETA, um demônio sempre faminto.</Level>

<Level id='160000'>Ele nao conseguia dizer se essa nova forma estava se alimentando de sua tristeza, ou se sua tristeza estava sendo fortalecida por sua nova forma.</Level>

<Level id='170000'>Foi uma experiencia miseravel e, no entanto... estranhamente, ele continuou.</Level>

<Level id='180000'>Com o tempo, ele comecou a encontrar uma estranha forca em sua total impotencia.</Level>

<Level id='190000'>Em sua mente, ele continuava voltando para todas as vidas passadas que havia vivido.</Level>

<Level id='200000'>Finalmente, uma grande descoberta foi feita.</Level>

<Level id='210000'>Na danca de Samsara,
os quebra-cabecas refletem os desafios da vida,
e nossas transformacoes ecoam a impermanencia da identidade.

Como monges, lidamos com a verdade agridoce
de que o sofrimento esta entrelacado na trama da existencia.

No entanto, na contemplacao tranquila,
encontramos a resiliencia para navegar pelo labirinto intricado da vida,
sabendo que nas sombras,
a luz da iluminacao nos espera.

OBRIGADO por jogar!</Level>



<Level id='1.14'>pc</Level>
<Level id='1.114'>movel</Level>

<Level id='2.14'>Pressione para mover as caixas de madeira</Level>
<Level id='2.114'>Pressione para mover as caixas de madeira</Level>

<Level id='3.14'>W ou Seta para cima para escalar uma arvore</Level>
<Level id='3.114'>Pressione a tecla de cima para subir em uma arvore</Level>

<Level id='4.14'>S ou Seta para baixo para deixar o tempo passar</Level>
<Level id='4.114'>Toque em Baixo para deixar o tempo passar</Level>

<Level id='5.14'>R para reiniciar</Level>
<Level id='5.114'>Toque para reiniciar</Level>

<Level id='6.14'>Direita e Esquerda para girar a roda Samsara, Cima e Baixo para ressurgir como uma nova forma de vida</Level>
<Level id='6.114'>Toque em Direita e Esquerda para girar a roda Samsara, Cima e Baixo para ressurgir como uma nova forma de vida</Level>

<Level id='7.14'>Apenas um humano pode tocar o sino</Level>
<Level id='7.114'>Apenas um humano pode tocar o sino</Level>

<Level id='8.14'>O JAVALI pode destruir alguns blocos</Level>
<Level id='8.114'>O JAVALI pode destruir alguns blocos</Level>

<Level id='9.14'>O PASSARO pode empurrar caixas leves e flutuar segurando W ou CIMA</Level>
<Level id='9.114'>O PASSARO pode empurrar caixas leves e flutuar segurando CIMA</Level>

<Level id='10.14'>O PASSARO pode usar ninhos como plataformas</Level>
<Level id='10.114'>O PASSARO pode usar ninhos como plataformas</Level>

<Level id='11.14'>Pressione Baixo para por um ovo como passaro</Level>
<Level id='11.114'>Pressione Baixo para por um ovo como passaro</Level>

<Level id='12.14'>A COBRA se move em quatro direcoes e pode empurrar caixas leves</Level>
<Level id='12.114'>A COBRA se move em quatro direcoes e pode empurrar caixas leves</Level>

<Level id='13.14'>A COBRA pode comer o ovo do PASSARO para crescer mais</Level>
<Level id='13.114'>A COBRA pode comer o ovo do PASSARO para crescer mais</Level>

<Level id='14.14'></Level>
<Level id='14.114'></Level>

<Level id='15.14'>Pressione S ou Baixo para se teletransportar entre as lapides. PRETA é purificada com o som do sino</Level>
<Level id='15.114'>Pressione Baixo para se teletransportar entre as lapides. PRETA é purificada com o som do sino</Level>

<Level id='16.14'>PRETA nao pode morrer</Level>
<Level id='16.114'>PRETA nao pode morrer</Level>

<Level id='17.14'>Voce so pode teletransportar lapides do mesmo tipo</Level>
<Level id='17.114'>Voce so pode teletransportar lapides do mesmo tipo</Level>



french-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
<Level id='99999'>Un jeune moine s'approcha de son maître et dit : "Maître, j'ai passe des annees a etudier les manuscrits, a mediter et a suivre votre sagesse, et pourtant je ne suis pas plus pres d'atteindre la verite que lorsque j'ai commence a etudier.

Dites-moi, quand atteindrai-je l'illumination ?"

Le maître dit : "Tu recherches le silence et pourtant tu refuses d'ecouter. Tu cherches la beaute et pourtant tu gardes les yeux fermes. Tes etudes n'ont meme pas commence."

Le moine ne fut pas satisfait de la reponse.

Avec un coeur fatigue, il se dirigea vers l'est a l'aube, laissant derriere lui ce qu'il avait de peu au temple.</Level>

<Level id='100000'>Les premiers jours furent remplis d'emerveillement. Le jeune moine decouvrit le monde dont il avait ete protege pendant tant d'annees.</Level>

<Level id='200000'>Son corps, si mal prepare a l'effort, se mettait maintenant en mouvement, courant et poussant.</Level>

<Level id='300000'>Il escaladait les arbres avec une dexterite surprenante, ivre de la sensation d'etre vivant.</Level>

<Level id='400000'>Le moine n'etait pas en manque de temps. Un peu de patience, et son environnement changeait rapidement.</Level>

<Level id='500000'>Mais... lentement, cette nouvelle liberte cessa d'etre une source de divertissement.</Level>

<Level id='600000'>"Il doit y avoir une autre forme d'existence, au-dela de cette enveloppe mortelle !" s'ecria le moine.</Level>

<Level id='700000'>La nouvelle forme donna au jeune moine une perspective etonnante sur la vie.</Level>

<Level id='800000'>Comme un sanglier, le moine cedait rapidement a ses pulsions les plus violentes.</Level>

<Level id='900000'>Mais bientot, meme cette existence n'offrit plus de divertissement. Il souhaita alors s'elever dans le ciel.</Level>

<Level id='1000000'>Ayant deja vecu une douzaine de vies, le moine commenca a remettre en question son vrai moi.</Level>

<Level id='1100000'>Etait-il un moine devenu oiseau ou un oiseau devenu moine ? Cette question circulaire n'avait ni commencement ni fin.</Level>

<Level id='1200000'>Une fois de plus, le moine se lassa de ses limites terrestres. Il chercha a se debarrasser de sa peau une fois de plus.</Level>

<Level id='1300000'>Contre toute attente, sa nouvelle existence ne fit rien pour apaiser son avidite. Il ressentait toujours la faim de la verite.</Level>

<Level id='1400000'>Pour toutes les formes que le moine avait atteintes, il ne pensait pas possible d'abandonner son ego et de devenir vraiment un avec le monde.</Level>

<Level id='1500000'>Submerge par la depression, le moine se sentit comme s'il se transformait en PRETA, un demon toujours affame.</Level>

<Level id='1600000'>Il ne pouvait dire si cette nouvelle forme se nourrissait de sa tristesse, ou si sa tristesse etait renforcee par sa nouvelle forme.</Level>

<Level id='1700000'>Ce fut une experience miserable et pourtant... etrangement, il continua.</Level>

<Level id='1800000'>Avec le temps, il commenca a trouver une etrange force dans son impuissance totale.</Level>

<Level id='1900000'>Dans son esprit, il continuait a revenir a toutes les vies passees qu'il avait vecues.</Level>

<Level id='2000000'>Enfin, une grande decouverte fut faite.</Level>

<Level id='2100000'>Dans la danse de Samsara,
les enigmes refletent les defis de la vie,
et nos transformations echoient a l'impermanence de l'identite.

En tant que moines, nous affrontons la verite aigre-douce
que la souffrance est tissee dans la trame de l'existence.

Pourtant, dans la contemplation tranquille,
nous trouvons la resilience pour naviguer dans le labyrinthe complexe de la vie,
sachant que dans les ombres,
la lumiere de l'illumination nous attend.

MERCI d'avoir joue !</Level>



<Level id='1.15'>pc</Level>
<Level id='1.115'>mobile</Level>

<Level id='2.15'>Appuyez pour deplacer les caisses en bois</Level>
<Level id='2.115'>Appuyez pour deplacer les caisses en bois</Level>

<Level id='3.15'>W ou Fleche Haut pour grimper a un arbre</Level>
<Level id='3.115'>Appuyez sur la touche Haut pour grimper a un arbre</Level>

<Level id='4.15'>S ou Fleche Bas pour laisser passer le temps</Level>
<Level id='4.115'>Appuyez sur Bas pour laisser passer le temps</Level>

<Level id='5.15'>R pour reinitialiser</Level>
<Level id='5.115'>Appuyez pour reinitialiser</Level>

<Level id='6.15'>DROITE et GAUCHE pour faire tourner la roue du Samsara, Haut et Bas pour ressusciter sous une nouvelle forme de vie</Level>
<Level id='6.115'>Appuyez sur DROITE et GAUCHE pour faire tourner la roue du Samsara, Haut et Bas pour ressusciter sous une nouvelle forme de vie</Level>

<Level id='7.15'>Seul un humain peut sonner la cloche</Level>
<Level id='7.115'>Seul un humain peut sonner la cloche</Level>

<Level id='8.15'>LE SANGLIER peut detruire certains blocs</Level>
<Level id='8.115'>LE SANGLIER peut detruire certains blocs</Level>

<Level id='9.15'>L'OISEAU peut pousser des caisses legeres et flotter en maintenant enfonce W ou Haut</Level>
<Level id='9.115'>L'OISEAU peut pousser des caisses legeres et flotter en maintenant enfonce Haut</Level>

<Level id='10.15'>L'OISEAU peut utiliser les nids comme plateformes</Level>
<Level id='10.115'>L'OISEAU peut utiliser les nids comme plateformes</Level>

<Level id='11.15'>Appuyez sur Bas pour pondre un oeuf en tant qu'oiseau</Level>
<Level id='11.115'>Appuyez sur Bas pour pondre un oeuf en tant qu'oiseau</Level>

<Level id='12.15'>Le SERPENT se deplace dans quatre directions et peut pousser des caisses legeres</Level>
<Level id='12.115'>Le SERPENT se deplace dans quatre directions et peut pousser des caisses legeres</Level>

<Level id='13.15'>Le SERPENT peut manger l'oeuf de l'OISEAU pour grandir</Level>
<Level id='13.115'>Le SERPENT peut manger l'oeuf de l'OISEAU pour grandir</Level>

<Level id='14.15'></Level>
<Level id='14.115'></Level>

<Level id='15.15'>Appuyez sur S ou Bas pour vous teleporter entre les pierres tombales. PRETA est purifie avec le son de la cloche</Level>
<Level id='15.115'>Appuyez sur Bas pour vous teleporter entre les pierres tombales. PRETA est purifie avec le son de la cloche</Level>

<Level id='16.15'>PRETA ne peut pas mourir</Level>
<Level id='16.115'>PRETA ne peut pas mourir</Level>

<Level id='17.15'>Vous ne pouvez teleporter que des pierres tombales du meme type</Level>
<Level id='17.115'>Vous ne pouvez teleporter que des pierres tombales du meme type</Level>




german-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
<Level id='999999'>Ein junger Monch naherte sich seinem Lehrer und sagte: "Meister, ich habe Jahre damit verbracht, die Manuskripte zu studieren, zu meditieren und Ihrer Weisheit zu folgen, und doch bin ich der Wahrheit nicht naher gekommen als zu Beginn meiner Studien.

Sagen Sie mir, wann werde ich die Erleuchtung erlangen?"

Der Meister sagte: "Du suchst die Stille und weigerst dich dennoch zuzuhoren. Du suchst die Schonheit und haltst doch deine Augen geschlossen. Deine Studien haben noch nicht einmal begonnen."

Der Monch war mit der Antwort nicht zufrieden.

Mit einem muden Herzen machte er sich bei Sonnenaufgang nach Osten auf, liess das Wenige, das er im Tempel hatte, zuruck.</Level>

<Level id='1000000'>Die ersten Tage waren voller Staunen. Der junge Monch entdeckte die Welt, die er so viele Jahre lang verschont hatte.</Level>

<Level id='2000000'>Sein Korper, so unzureichend auf Anstrengung vorbereitet, bewegte sich nun, lief und drangte.</Level>

<Level id='3000000'>Er kletterte mit erstaunlicher Geschicklichkeit auf Baume, berauscht von dem Gefuhl, lebendig zu sein.</Level>

<Level id='4000000'>Dem Monch fehlte es nicht an Zeit. Ein wenig Geduld, und seine Umgebung veranderte sich schnell.</Level>

<Level id='5000000'>Aber... langsam, aber sicher horte diese neue Freiheit auf, eine Quelle der Unterhaltung zu sein.</Level>

<Level id='6000000'>"Es muss eine andere Existenzform geben, jenseits dieser sterblichen Hulle!" rief der Monch aus.</Level>

<Level id='7000000'>Die neue Form gab dem jungen Monch eine uberraschende Perspektive auf das Leben.</Level>

<Level id='8000000'>Als Wildschwein gab der Monch schnell seinen gewalttatigeren Impulsen nach.</Level>

<Level id='9000000'>Aber bald bot auch diese Existenz keine Unterhaltung mehr. Als nachstes wunschte er sich, in den Himmel zu fliegen.</Level>

<Level id='10000000'>Nachdem der Monch bereits ein Dutzend Leben gelebt hatte, begann er, sein wahres Selbst in Frage zu stellen.</Level>

<Level id='11000000'>War er ein Monch, der zu einem Vogel wurde, oder ein Vogel, der zu einem Monch wurde? Diese kreisende Frage hatte keinen Anfang und kein Ende.</Level>

<Level id='12000000'>Wieder einmal wurde der Monch seiner irdischen Begrenzungen uberdrussig. Er strebte danach, seine Haut erneut abzulegen.</Level>

<Level id='13000000'>Entgegen aller Erwartungen tat seine neue Existenz nichts, um seine Gier zu stillen. Er verspurte immer noch Hunger nach der Wahrheit.</Level>

<Level id='14000000'>Fur alle Formen, die der Monch angenommen hatte, hielt er es nicht fur moglich, sein Ego loszulassen und wirklich eins mit der Welt zu werden.</Level>

<Level id='15000000'>Uberwaltigt von Depressionen fuhlte sich der Monch, als ob er sich in einen PRETA, einen immer hungrigen Damon, verwandelte.</Level>

<Level id='16000000'>Er konnte nicht sagen, ob diese neue Form sich von seinem Kummer ernahrte oder ob sein Kummer durch seine neue Form gestarkt wurde.</Level>

<Level id='17000000'>Es war eine elende Erfahrung und doch... merkwurdigerweise machte er weiter.</Level>

<Level id='18000000'>Mit der Zeit begann er, eine seltsame Starke in seiner vollkommenen Ohnmacht zu finden.</Level>

<Level id='19000000'>In seinem Geist kehrte er immer wieder zu all den vergangenen Leben zuruck, die er gelebt hatte.</Level>

<Level id='20000000'>Schliesslich wurde ein Durchbruch erzielt.</Level>

<Level id='21000000'>Im Tanz von Samsara
spiegeln Ratsel die Herausforderungen des Lebens wider,
und unsere Transformationen hallen die Verganglichkeit der Identitat wider.

Als Monche ringen wir mit der bittersussen Wahrheit,
dass das Leiden in das Gewebe des Daseins verwoben ist.

Dennoch finden wir in der ruhigen Betrachtung
die Widerstandsfahigkeit, um uns durch das komplexe Labyrinth des Lebens zu navigieren,
wissend, dass im Schatten
das Licht der Erleuchtung wartet.

DANKE, dass du gespielt hast!</Level>


<Level id='1.16'>pc</Level>
<Level id='1.116'>mobil</Level>

<Level id='2.16'>Drucken Sie, um die Holzkisten zu bewegen</Level>
<Level id='2.116'>Drucken Sie, um die Holzkisten zu bewegen</Level>

<Level id='3.16'>W oder Pfeil nach oben, um einen Baum zu erklimmen</Level>
<Level id='3.116'>Drucken Sie die Taste nach oben, um einen Baum zu erklimmen</Level>

<Level id='4.16'>S oder Pfeil nach unten, um die Zeit verstreichen zu lassen</Level>
<Level id='4.116'>Tippen Sie nach unten, um die Zeit verstreichen zu lassen</Level>

<Level id='5.16'>R zum Zurucksetzen</Level>
<Level id='5.116'>Tippen Sie zum Zurucksetzen</Level>

<Level id='6.16'>RECHTS und LINKS, um das Samsara-Rad zu drehen, Oben und Unten, um als neue Lebensform wiederzukehren</Level>
<Level id='6.116'>Tippen Sie auf RECHTS und LINKS, um das Samsara-Rad zu drehen, Oben und Unten, um als neue Lebensform wiederzukehren</Level>

<Level id='7.16'>Nur ein Mensch kann die Glocke lauten</Level>
<Level id='7.116'>Nur ein Mensch kann die Glocke lauten</Level>

<Level id='8.16'>DAS WILD kann einige Blocke zerstoren</Level>
<Level id='8.116'>DAS WILD kann einige Blocke zerstoren</Level>

<Level id='9.16'>DER VOGEL kann leichte Kisten schieben und schweben, indem er W oder OBEN gedruckt halt</Level>
<Level id='9.116'>DER VOGEL kann leichte Kisten schieben und schweben, indem er OBEN gedruckt halt</Level>

<Level id='10.16'>DER VOGEL kann Nester als Plattformen verwenden</Level>
<Level id='10.116'>DER VOGEL kann Nester als Plattformen verwenden</Level>

<Level id='11.16'>Tippen Sie nach unten, um als Vogel ein Ei zu legen</Level>
<Level id='11.116'>Tippen Sie nach unten, um als Vogel ein Ei zu legen</Level>

<Level id='12.16'>DIE SCHLANGE bewegt sich in vier Richtungen und kann leichte Kisten schieben</Level>
<Level id='12.116'>DIE SCHLANGE bewegt sich in vier Richtungen und kann leichte Kisten schieben</Level>

<Level id='13.16'>DIE SCHLANGE kann das Ei des VOGELS essen, um langer zu werden</Level>
<Level id='13.116'>DIE SCHLANGE kann das Ei des VOGELS essen, um langer zu werden</Level>

<Level id='14.16'></Level>
<Level id='14.116'></Level>

<Level id='15.16'>Tippen Sie auf S oder nach unten, um zwischen Grabsteinen zu teleportieren. PRETA wird mit dem Glockenklang gereinigt</Level>
<Level id='15.116'>Tippen Sie nach unten, um zwischen Grabsteinen zu teleportieren. PRETA wird mit dem Glockenklang gereinigt</Level>

<Level id='16.16'>PRETA kann nicht sterben</Level>
<Level id='16.116'>PRETA kann nicht sterben</Level>

<Level id='17.16'>Sie konnen nur Grabsteine des gleichen Typs teleportieren</Level>
<Level id='17.116'>Sie konnen nur Grabsteine des gleichen Typs teleportieren</Level>


