<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<stringresources>
    <languages>
        <language>en</language>
        <language>sk</language>
        <language>es</language>
        <language>cz</language>
        <language>de</language>
        <language>it</language>
        <language>fr</language>
        <language>ru</language>
        <language>pt</language>
        <language>tr</language>
    </languages>
    <strings>
        <string id="1" index="0">
            <en>en</en>
            <sk>sk</sk>
            <es>es</es>
            <cz>cz</cz>
            <de>de</de>
            <it>it</it>
            <fr>fr</fr>
            <ru>ru</ru>
            <pt>pt</pt>
            <tr>tr</tr>
        </string>
        <string id="INSTRUCTIONS" index="1">
            <en>Aim of the game\nOwn more pieces than your opponent. You win by making your colour dominant on the board. The game is over when neither player has a move.\n\nBasic rules\nEach reversi piece has a black side and a white side. On your turn, you place one piece on the board with your colour facing up. You must place the piece so that an opponent's piece is flanked by your pieces. All of the opponent's pieces between your pieces are then reversed to your colour (captured). You can capture vertical, horizontal and diagonal rows of pieces.\n\nThe circles\nThe numbers in the circles show how many opponent's pieces will be captured. They also show spaces available.\n\nSettings\nYou can choose your colour and difficulty of computer controlled opponent.</en>
            <de>Spielziel\nBesitze mehr Steine als dein Gegner. Du gewinnst, indem du deine Farbe zur dominanten auf dem Spielfeld machst. Das Spiel ist beendet, wenn kein Spieler einen Zug mehr hat.\n\nGrundregeln\nJeder Reversi-Stein hat eine schwarze und eine weiße Seite. In deinem Zug platzierst du einen Stein auf das Spielbrett, wobei deine Seite nach oben zeigt. Du musst den Stein so platzieren, dass sich ein gegnerischer Stein zwischen zwei Steinen von dir befindet. Alle Steine deines Gegners zwischen deinen Steinen werden umgedreht, sodass sie deine Farbe zeigen. (Sie wurden erobert.) Du kannst waagerechte, senkrechte und diagonale Steinreihen erobern.\n\nDie Kreise\nDie Zahlen in den Kreisen zeigen an, wie viele gegnerische Steine erobert werden. Sie zeigen auch die verfügbaren Stellen an. \n\nEinstellungen\nDu kannst deine Farbe und die Stärke des Computergegners wählen.</de>
            <es>Objetivo del juego\nTener más fichas de tu color que el rival. Ganas si tu color domina el tablero. La partida termina cuando ninguno de los dos jugadores pueda realizar ningún movimiento.\n\nReglas básicas\nCada ficha de Reversi tiene una cara negra y otra blanca. Cuando te toque, coloca una ficha en el tablero con tu color hacia arriba. Debes colocarla de manera que haya fichas enemigas entre la ficha que coloques y otra que tengas ya en el tablero. Todas las fichas del rival situadas entre tus fichas pasan a ser de tu color (se capturan). Puedes capturar fichas en sentido vertical, horizontal y diagonal.\n\nLos círculos\nLos números de los círculos indican cuántas fichas del rival capturarás. También indican los espacios disponibles. \n\nAjustes\nPuedes elegir tu color y la dificultad del rival controlado por el ordenador.</es>
            <fr>But du jeu\nPossédez plus de pièces que votre adversaire. Vous gagnez lorsque votre couleur domine le plateau. La partie est terminée quand plus aucun joueur ne peut faire de coup.\n\nRègles de base\nChaque pièce de reversi a un côté noir et un côté blanc. Lors de votre tour, placez une pièce sur le plateau, votre couleur face visible. Vous devez placer votre pièce à côté d'une pièce de votre adversaire. Toutes les pièces de votre adversaire qui se trouvent entre vos pièces sont ensuite retournées pour être de votre couleur (capturées). Vous pouvez capturer des rangées de pièces à la verticale, à l'horizontale et en diagonale.\n\nLes cercles\nLes nombres dans les cercles indiquent combien de pièces de l'adversaire seront capturées. Ils montrent également les cases disponibles. \n\nParamètres\nVous pouvez choisir votre couleur et la difficulté de votre adversaire contrôlé par ordinateur.</fr>
            <it>Obiettivo del gioco\nPossiedi più pedine del tuo avversario. Vinci rendendo dominante il tuo colore sulla scacchiera. Il gioco termina quando nessuno dei due giocatori può fare altre mosse. \n\nRegole base\nOgni pedina ha un lato nero e un lato bianco. Nel tuo turno, metti una pedina sulla scacchiera con il colore rivolto verso l'alto. Devi posizionare la pedina in modo che una pedina dell'avversario sia affiancata dalle tue pedine. Tutte le pedine dell'avversario tra le tue pedine vengono quindi rovesciate e diventano del tuo colore (catturate). È possibile acquisire file di pedine verticali, orizzontali e diagonali.\n\nI cerchi\nI numeri nei cerchi mostrano quante pedine dell'avversario saranno catturate. Mostrano anche gli spazi disponibili. \n\nImpostazioni\nPuoi scegliere il colore e la difficoltà dell'avversario controllato dal computer.</it>
            <pt>Objetivo do jogo\nTer mais peças que seu oponente Você ganha, tornando sua cor dominante no tabuleiro. O jogo termina quando nenhum dos jogadores se move.\n\nRegras básicas\nCada peça reversi tem um lado preto e um lado branco. Na sua vez, você coloca uma peça no tabuleiro com a cor voltada para cima. Você deve colocar a peça para que a peça de um oponente seja flanqueada por suas peças. Todas as peças do oponente entre as peças são invertidas para a sua cor (capturadas). Você pode capturar linhas verticais, horizontais e diagonais de peças.\n\nOs círculos\nOs números nos círculos mostram quantas peças do oponente serão capturadas. Eles também mostram os espaços disponíveis.\n\nConfigurações\nVocê pode escolher sua cor e dificuldade do oponente controlado por computador.</pt>
            <ru>Цель игры\nПолучите больше фигур, чем ваш противник. Вы выигрываете, если ваш цвет будет доминирующим на доске. Игра закончиться, когда ни у одного игрока не останется ходов.\n\nОсновные правила\nКаждая фигурка имеет черную и белую сторону. В свою очередь вы кладете одну фигуру на доску цветом вверх. Вы должны поместить фигуру так, чтобы фигура противника была между вашими фигурами. Все фигуры противника, которые попали между вашими фигурами поменяют цвет (захваченные). Вы можете захватывать вертикальные, горизонтальные и диагональные линии.\n\nДополнительные круги\nЧисла в кругах показывают, сколько фигур противника будет захвачено. Они также показывают свободные места.\n\nНастройки\nВы можете выбрать свой цвет и сложность противника. </ru>
            <tr/>
        </string>
        <string id="PAUSE" index="2">
            <en>PAUSE</en>
            <de>PAUSE</de>
            <es>PAUSA</es>
            <fr>PAUSE</fr>
            <it>PAUSA</it>
            <pt>PAUSA</pt>
            <ru>ПАУЗА</ru>
            <tr>DURAKLAT</tr>
        </string>
        <string id="VERSION" index="3">
            <en>Version</en>
            <sk/>
            <es>Versión</es>
            <cz/>
            <de>Version</de>
            <it>Versione</it>
            <fr>Version</fr>
            <ru>Версия</ru>
            <pt>Versão</pt>
            <tr/>
        </string>
        <string id="PAUSED" index="4">
            <en>Paused</en>
            <sk/>
            <es>Pausa</es>
            <cz/>
            <de>Angehalten</de>
            <it>Pausa</it>
            <fr>Pause</fr>
            <ru>Пауза</ru>
            <pt>Pausado</pt>
            <tr/>
        </string>
        <string id="NO_MOVES" index="5">
            <en>No moves available!</en>
            <sk/>
            <es>¡No quedan movimientos!</es>
            <cz/>
            <de>Keine Züge möglich!</de>
            <it>Nessuna mossa disponibile!</it>
            <fr>Aucun coup possible!</fr>
            <ru>Нет доступных ходов!</ru>
            <pt>Não há movimentos disponíveis</pt>
            <tr/>
        </string>
    </strings>
</stringresources>
